bilingualmonkeys.com 2018-11-22

# Privacy Policy for Bilingual Monkeys

At Bilingual Monkeys, we recognize that the privacy of your personal information is very important. This privacy policy describes the types of personal information that we receive and collect when you visit this site and how that information is safeguarded and used. Your personal information is never sold to third parties.

## Log Files

Like most websites, we make use of log files, which merely log visitors to the site. The information in the log files includes your IP (internet protocol) address, ISP (internet service provider), browser used to visit this site, the date/time of your visit, and which pages you visited. This information is used to administer the site and analyze the use of this site. None of this logged data includes information that is personally identifiable.

## Cookies and Web Beacons

We use cookies to store information about visitors’ preferences, to record user-specific information on which pages are accessed or visited, and to personalize or customize our web page content based upon your browser type or other information sent via your browser.

We also use third party advertisements on Bilingual Monkeys to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

## DoubleClick DART Cookie

We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (“interest based targeting”).

The ads served are targeted based on your previous browsing history. (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting London, you may see London hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about sports.) DART uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers.

For further information on DoubleClick advertising, and opting-out of such advertising on all sites that make use of it, please visit:  
<http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx>

## Third Party Privacy Policies

You should consult the respective privacy policies of third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. The privacy policy for Bilingual Monkeys does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

## Measuring Website Usage

We use Google Analytics to collect information about how visitors use this site. Google Analytics stores information such as what pages you visit, how long you are on the site, how you got here, what you click on, and information about your web browser.

IP addresses are masked (only a portion is stored) and personal information is only reported in aggregate. We do not allow Google to use or share our analytics data for any purpose other than providing us with analytics information.

## Newsletter Subscription

If you [subscribe](http://bilingualmonkeys.com/subscribe/) to the Bilingual Monkeys newsletter, your name and email address is added to our newsletter mailing list, which is managed by MailChimp. Our newsletter is sent out on a regular basis and you may unsubscribe at any time.

## Amazon Affiliate Disclosure

Bilingual Monkeys is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program which enables websites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com.

## Children’s Information

We believe it is important to provide added protection for children online. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children to observe, participate in and/or monitor and guide their online activity. This website does not collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13.

## Consent

By using our website, you hereby consent to our privacy policy and agree to its terms.

## Update

This Privacy Policy was last updated on Saturday, June 30, 2018.
